In a world on the brink of war. You either march
to one tune or dance to another.
Swing Kids is a music, drama film directed by Thomas Carter.
The story of a close-knit group of young kids in Nazi Germany
who listen to banned swing music from the US.
Soon dancing and fun leads to more difficult choices as the
Nazis begin tightening the grip on Germany.
Each member of the group is forced to face some tough
choices about right, wrong, and survival.
Peter Müller, played by Robert Sean Leonard.
Thomas Berger, played by Christian Bale.
Arvid, played by Frank Whaley.
Frau Müller, played by Barbara Hershey.
Evey, played by Tushka Bergen.
Willi Müller, played by David Tom.
Swing Kids is a 1993 American historical drama film directed by Thomas Carter in his feature film debut, and
starring Robert Sean Leonard, Christian Bale, Frank Whaley, Barbara Hershey and Kenneth Branagh.
The title refers to a youth subculture in Nazi Germany, in which teenagers embraced
American and British swing music in defiance of the Nazi regime.
The film follows two high school students in their attempt to be swing kids by night and
Hitler Youth by day, a decision that acutely impacts their friends and families.
The film was released by Buena Vista Pictures on March 5, 1993.
It received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of suicide, world war ii,
antisemitism, anti-nazi resistance, swing dancing.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.